♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
Woohoo!
You’re really doing
a great job, Jeremie!
XANA better be
behaving himself
now that we’ve
got these things!
Whoa!
Hah ha!
Be careful all the same!
Don’t worry, Einstein.
I know how to ride!
No way I’m gonna
let Ulrich beat me!
Wahoo!
Oh, no you don’t.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Hah ha!
Odd, I didn’t have time
to perfect the program
that calculates trajectory!
Yeah!
Huh?
(YELLS)
(CHUCKLES)
Odd!
Are you okay?
Oh, yeah.
There’s still some work to do
on the Overboard, Jeremie.
Maybe it’s the rider
who needs the work!
What happened, Odd?
You miss a step?
(CACKLES)
Very funny.
I’d like to see you
on an Overboard!
I guess surfing’s
not my thing.
Uh, sorry to interrupt your
fascinating conversation,
but it looks like XANA
has spotted you.
There’s something
coming your way!
(BEEPING)
But that’s really weird.
I…I can’t tell what it is.
Hey.
what’s that?
I don’t know, but it
looks like trouble.
Big time.
I’ve never seen a monster
like that one before.
XANA must’ve just created it.
In any case, it says here
that it’s got more life points
than the others.
(GASPS)
(SCREECHING)
Jeremie, how about
reprogramming our vehicles?
I’m on it already.
But it’s gonna take time.
On my signal.
I’ll go first
And I’m gonna keep it busy.
Now!
Aelita, there’s a deactivated
tower not far away.
Direction -- north by northwest.
Get out of there and
come and meet me,
but hurry up!
Hey, you overgrown spider!
Looking for me?
(SCREECHES)
Odd, you just lost 20 life points.
It’s got a powerful laser!
What does it take
to destroy this thing?
Vehicles ready.
Well, it’s about time!
Come on! I’m doing my best!
Let me go first.
Go on.
We’ll be watching you.
Laser arrows!
This thing is really unbeatable!
Need a hand?
Laser arrows!
(SCREECHES)
If XANA’s gonna start
programming new monsters,
it means our troubles, guys,
have only just begun.
Anyway, Einstein,
one thing is sure --
you’re gonna have to
program our vehicles faster.
Otherwise, we don’t stand a chance
against those tarantulas!
Your aunt what?
Tarantulas! The new monsters.
I like to give my enemies a name.
What worries me is
that our friend, XANA,
has obviously found a way
to increase his power.
You think he’s still evolving?
Maybe so.
In any case, from now on,
we have to be ready for
anything and everything.
Maybe I’d better
get back to Lyoko.
If XANA activates a tower,
I’d better be there.
Uh, should we tell her?
Hm?
Well, of course
we should tell her!
Why keep good news
like that a secret?
Keep what a secret?
Would someone please
tell me what’s going on?
Over the past few weeks,
I’ve spent all of my time
developing the vehicles and
an antivirus to free you from XANA,
and I also perfected
a whole new program
for detecting activated towers.
A super scanner!
Much more accurate
than the old one.
With instant detection.
Meaning -- you don’t have to
stay on Lyoko all the time!
So I’m gonna live…
Here. With us.
We’ve already enrolled you
as a boarder at the school.
Everything’s all set up.
We wanted to surprise you.
I…
This is so wonderful!
I can’t believe it!
And this is your room.
It’s not very big, but
you’ll like it here, Miss, u
Stones.
Aelita Stones.
Like the rock group.
I’m Odd’s cousin from Canada.
Oh.
So, Aelita, breakfast
starts at 7 AM,
and dinner’s at 7 PM.
It’s against the rules
to be in your room
between 8 AM and 4:30 PM
You can ask your friends,
Della Robbia,
Stern, and Belpois,
to fill you in on
the rest of the rules.
That is, if they can
remember them.
Hmph.
I don’t want to
hear another word
about the school newspaper.
This excursion is for eighth-
and ninth-graders only.
Is that clear?
(SIGHS)
Oh, rats.
(GROWLS)
Kiwi!
Stop wiggling around!
Five more minutes, and you can
run around all you want to.
Hey. Is everything okay, Aelita?
Are you all settled in?
Yes, I am.
And I love my room.
Hey, what’s this field trip
everybody’s talking about?
We’re gonna make
a biodiversity scrapbook.
Misses Hertz wants
us to take pictures
and to draw plants and flowers.
That kind of thing.
You and I have been
paired up to work together.
Great!
Anyone seen Ulrich?
He’s under the arches.
I think he’s waiting for Yumi.
Okay. Yumi, there’s
something I have to tell you.
No, that doesn’t sound right.
Um…Yumi, there’s
something serious
you and I have
to talk about.
No, she’ll freak out if I say that.
Right.
Yumi! You and I have to--
Yumi!
I-I have something to tell you.
Yo, Yumi!
Uh, Misses Hertz said okay.
We can work together
on the field trip!
Hey.
William, do you know Ulrich?
Huh.
Oh, you’re Ulrich Stern.
Yumi mentioned you.
Ready to go?
Coming.
Didn’t you have
something to tell me?
I’ll tell you later.
See ya later!
Hey! What are you doing?
Everyone’s leaving!
We have to be back by six.
Who is that guy.
Oh, who? Him?
That’s William.
He’s the new guy.
He got kicked out
of his last school.
He’s totally cool.
Did you know that trees
grow new branches
from one year to the next
according to an
exponential ratio of 1.6?
1.618 to be exact.
It’s the golden ratio.
Say, do you think nature obeys
nonlinear equation systems?
Can you believe those two?
Who do they think
they are, anyway?
Mr. and Mrs. Einstein?
Uh...who?
Hey, Sissi, where are you going?
The woods are this way.
Yes, but the stores are that way.
But we’re supposed to draw plants.
There’s a florist
in the shopping center.
Erm…
Oh.
There aren’t any
monsters in these woods!
That only happens in fairy tales
or in silly horror pictures.
(CHUCKLES) The kind that Odd likes!
You don’t like horror films?
I find them inaccurate
scientifically speaking.
Anyway, I don’t have time
to go to the movies.
I’ve got my work
cut out for me with XANA.
Huh?
Oh, no. I don’t believe it!
I left my laptop in my room.
What if XANA attacks?
Well, run back and get it!
I’ll just keep working by myself.
Anyway, with the drawings
we’ve already done,
I’m sure we’ll get
the highest grade.
Yeah. Be right back!
Bye.
Oh, stop freaking out!
You know Yumi’s
crazy about you!
That’s what you think.
Actually, I have no idea.
I can’t figure you guys out.
Are you going out together or not?
Um…not really.
It’s complicated.
Right now, I’ll bet he’s
completely snowing her.
I wouldn’t really
call myself a rebel.
I’m just a little…rebellious.
Well, you did manage to get yourself
kicked out of your last school
putting posters all over the place.
I object, your honor!
Extenuating circumstances!
They were love letters.
You mean love makes you crazy?
Makes me totally insane.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
(LEAVES RUSTLING)
Monsters only exist in fairy tales.
Monsters only exist in fairy tales!
(HOWLING)
(BEEPING)
Just what I was afraid of.
XANA’s attacking!
I don’t think I have
to remind you
that we haven’t done a single
drawing since we got here.
I don’t even want to think about
the grade we’re gonna get.
Go ahead. You draw.
You’re better at it than I am.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Jeremie?
I’m at school.
XANA’s attacking.
I’ll head for the factory,
but you guys have to go
pick up Aelita on the way.
No problem. We’ll go and get her.
I left her on the red trail.
Is Yumi with you?
No.
I’d rather you call her yourself.
See you in a minute.
Actually, I don’t do anything halfway.
No way -- it’s all
or nothing with me.
I just can’t bring
myself to be sensible.
But, hey,
being sensible
is just not sensible.
You stole that line
from the Subsonics.
You listen to them?
Yeah, they’re awesome.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Yes?
Well, It’s about time we
got back to work, huh?
Yumi?
Yumi!
(PANTING)
“The Hermitage.”
Is…is anybody home?
Are you sure this is the place?
That’s what Jeremie told me.
Look!
Let’s follow him!
Are you sure?
He may be a little dumb,
but he does have a good nose.
(CRACKLING)
Huh?
Hiyah!
Hey!
Nervous, aren’t we.
What a warm welcome. Nice.
Yumi, we can’t find Aelita!
♪ (PLAYING TWINKLE, TWINKLE, LITTLE STAR)
(ATONAL)
Don’t tell me you
haven’t found her yet!
What have you guys been doing?
She may be in big danger!
Chill, Jeremie, okay?
We’re doing everything we can!
Who knows. Maybe Aelita
just went back to school.
Kiwi led us to an
old house in the woods.
We’re gonna take a look inside.
We’ll call you back
if we have any news.
Aelita?
It’s locked!
No signal.
Look out!
That way.
Are you thinking
what I’m thinking?
XANA.
Yeah, and that means Aelita
must be here somewhere.
Hey, Odd! Watch out!
Looks like XANA’s trying
to lead us somewhere.
-Aelita!
Don’t worry, princess. We’re here.
Ulrich.
It’s a trap.
XANA. He’s going to--
Get Aelita out!
You’ll be cooked alive if we
don’t get you out of there!
Odd!
Run to the factory with Aelita.
Deactivate the tower.
It’s our only hope.
Come on.
I knew it.
Now we’ll have to
go above ground.
Wait!
Kiwi!
Odd.
There’s a passage over there.
I...I think it leads to the sewers.
This is no time for jokes, Aelita.
I’m not joking, Odd.
I’m sure.
Wow, incredible!
How did you know about this?
Yumi, I um…
Forget it, Ulrich.
I should’ve told you
about William sooner.
Yeah, that would’ve been better.
Aelita!
I was really worried.
No time to lose, Einstein.
Otherwise, Ulrich and Yumi
will end up like dim sum!
Okay. Head for the scanners.
I’ll start the process.
Transfer Aelita.
Transfer Odd.
Scanner Aelita.
Scanner Odd.
Virtualization.
Aelita, the overwing is for you.
Our taxis are waiting for us.
Let’s go.
Tower dead ahead.
Be careful.
You’ve got two
tarantulas guarding it.
I’ll never be able
to fight my way
through two of
those horrors!
Maybe I can lure
away one of them.
Oh~
Aelita, what are you
planning on doing?
She’s gonna
steal the show.
Go ahead.
I won’t look.
(SCREECHING)
Well, my little monster friends,
did you miss me?
Yoo-hoo!
Surprise!
They’re not all that invincible.
Uh-oh.
Jeremie, I’m all out of ammo.
Okay, I’ll reload you. Be patient.
We’re gonna have to
keep the monsters busy.
Wait for my signal to run.
Gotcha.
Yu…Yumi…
I…um…
What’s, um,
really going on
between you
and…William?
Nothing at all.
He’s just…just a friend.
Done!
You’re fully loaded!
Great, Jeremie!
I’m breaking off.
Aelita!
Now!
(PANTING)
Yes!
Yeah!
(SHATTERS)
Tower deactivated.
Return to the past now.
Congratulations, Miss Delmas.
You found an Amazonian Yuka
here in our woods?
Uh…yeah!
And it wasn’t easy, either!
Is that so?
Well, I think it’s going to be
much easier grading you work.
Zero.
Huh!?
So, did you manage to get
any drawing done this time?
Yeah.
But I had to drag Ulrich
far away from Yumi and William.
Going back in time
didn’t change anything there.
I went to check out that
house, The Hermitage.
Nothing to report.
It’s gone back to being
a normal house.
Abandoned, but normal.
It’s so weird.
All those visions I had there.
Not to mention the
underground passage
that you knew about.
It’s as if I had already
seen that house.
In a dream.
A new mystery
to solve for us.
By the way, uh, Aelita,
This is for you.
It’s to keep us one
step ahead of XANA.
For me?
This way, we can
always stay in touch.
Uh, I thought that
pink would suit you.
Wow! Looks cool!
It matches your hair!
(LAUGHS)
Thank you, Jeremie!
There you go!
You’re like a regular
school kid now!
(LAUGHTER)
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO